<section>
	<title>
	pppoe
	</title>
	<screen>
<![CDATA[
我们常用的ADSL拨号其实就是在使用PPPOE
]]>
	</screen>
	<section>
		<title>
		配置
		</title>
		<screen>
<![CDATA[
[root@zenboss ~]# adsl-setup

Welcome to the ADSL client setup. First, I will run some checks on

your system to make sure the PPPoE client is installed properly...


LOGIN NAME

Enter your Login Name (default root): SZ1234567

#网络接入商(ISP)给你的用户名


INTERFACE

Enter the Ethernet interface connected to the ADSL modem

For Solaris, this is likely to be something like /dev/hme0.

For Linux, it will be ethX, where 'X' is a number.

(default eth0): eth0

#用来adsl拨号的网卡代码


Do you want the link to come up on demand, or stay up continuously?

If you want it to come up on demand, enter the idle time in seconds

after which the link should be dropped. If you want the link to

stay up permanently, enter 'no' (two letters, lower-case.)

NOTE: Demand-activated links do not interact well with dynamic IP

addresses. You may have some problems with demand-activated links.

Enter the demand value (default no):

#直接回车


DNS

Enter the DNS information here: 202.96.128.86

Enter the secondary DNS server address here: 202.96.134.166

#DNS地址

#会写到/etc/resolv.conf中


PASSWORD

Please enter your Password:

Please re-enter your Password:

#输入两次ISP给你ADSL拨号的密码


USERCTRL

Please enter 'yes' (two letters, lower-case.) if you want to allow

normal user to start or stop DSL connection (default yes): no

#让使用者无法打开或关闭ADSL拨号(让使用者无法改变ADSL拨号状态)


The firewall choices are:

0 - NONE: This script will not set any firewall rules. You are responsible

　　　　　for ensuring the security of your machine. You are STRONGLY

　　　　　recommended to use some kind of firewall rules.

1 - STANDALONE: Appropriate for a basic stand-alone web-surfing workstation

2 - MASQUERADE: Appropriate for a machine acting as an Internet gateway

　　　　　　　　for a LAN

Choose a type of firewall (0-2): 0

#防火墙等级,这里用0,就是不使用防火墙,以后可以使用LINUX的防火墙实现此功能


Start this connection at boot time

Do you want to start this connection at boot time?

Please enter no or yes (default no):yes

#是否随系统启动而拨号



Ethernet Interface: eth0

User name: T1234567

Activate-on-demand: No

Primary DNS: 168.95.1.1

Secondary DNS: 139.175.10.20

Firewalling: NONE

User Control: no

Accept these settings and adjust configuration files (y/n)? y

#写入(保存)配置,没有问题就确认


Adjusting /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-ppp0

Adjusting /etc/resolv.conf

　(But first backing it up to /etc/resolv.conf.bak)

Adjusting /etc/ppp/chap-secrets and /etc/ppp/pap-secrets

　(But first backing it up to /etc/ppp/chap-secrets.bak)

　(But first backing it up to /etc/ppp/pap-secrets.bak)


#ifcfg-ppp0,/etc/ppp/pppoe.conf : 以上配置就保存在这个文件里

#resolv.conf : DNS服务器地址文件,似乎上面的配置会改动这个文件,而且帮你备份原有的

#pap-secrets, /etc/ppp/chap-secrets : 我们上面输入的密码就在这个文件里 
]]>
		</screen>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>
		使用PPPOE拨号 
		</title>
		<screen>
<![CDATA[
[root@zenboss ~]# adsl-start 
]]>
		</screen>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>
		关闭PPPOE拨号 
		</title>
		<screen>
<![CDATA[
[root@zenboss ~]# adsl-stop 
]]>
		</screen>
	</section>
</section>
